Guide to the "Boys From Houston" research files, 1963-1989 MS 686
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
"Boys From Houston" research files
1963-1989
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Ayo, Vicki Welch
MS 686
0.25 Linear Feet (1 box)
0.178 Gigabytes Nearline access: MS0686aip_001 (0.179 GB)
0.021 Gigabytes Nearline access: MS0686aip_002 (0.021 GB)
These research files contain the newspaper clippings, ephemera, and photographs used by Vicki Welch Ayo and William C. DeLaVergne.
Biographical / Historical
Starting with "Boys Fom Houston: The Spirit and Image of Our Music," Vicki Welch Ayo wrote about the varied Houston music scenes of the 1960s-1970s. She and fellow writer William C. DeLaVergne followed it up with "Boys From Houston II: Deep in the Heart." In 2016, Ayo published a third book in the series, "Boys From Houston III: Groove-In." The books aim to chronicle Houston's and by extension the region's thriving music scenes and their affects on the community.
Conditions Governing Access
This material is open for research. Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Accruals
Additional materials are expected for this collection.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Vicki Welch Ayo in February 2017.
Index Terms
Subjects
Women; Folk music -- Texas -- Houston; Music; Authors
Document Types
Folk music; Folk-rock music
Subjects (Persons)
Ayo, Vicki Welch
- Series I: Physical files, 1963-1989
  - The Balladiers, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Corky's (CD), 1970s-1980s (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Houston Folklore Society, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Jewish Community Center, 1960s (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Kerrville Folk Festival, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - La Maison de Cafe, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Music venues, ca. 1965, 1986-1989 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - The Old Quarter, 1960s, 1980s (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Sand Mountain Coffee House, 1965-1975 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Sound Investment, 2020 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Toad Hall, Austin, 1970s (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Series II: Digital files, 1960s
  - 13th Floor Elevators
    Scope and Contents
    The items in these files consist of digital images used for research. All the files are jpgs.
  - Andrus Studios
  - Bill Narum
  - Billy Joe Shaver
  - B.J. Thomas
  - Blaze Foley
  - Buttermilk Bottom
  - Champagne Brothers
  - Coastliners
  - Corky's
  - Countdown 5
  - David Adickes
  - Deuces Wild
  - Dimensions Sound Investment
  - Fever Tree
  - Gene Thomas
  - Ginger Valley
  - The Glass Kans
  - Lightnin' Hopkins
  - Love Street
  - Magic Ring
  - La Maison
  - Mance Lipscomb
  - Matchbox
  - Moving Sidewalks
  - Music Machine
  - Naked Letus
  - Navasota
  - Playboys of Edinburg
  - Rancho Bebop / Billy Block
  - Rocky Erickson / Roy Head
  - Shaydes
  - The Children
  - Theodore's
  - Thursday's Children
  - Townes Van Zandt